<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
   	<title>RealJenius.com - Tag: cloudfoundry</title>
   
   <link>http://realjenius.com</link>
   <description>I'm a software developer in the game industry, and have been (for better or worse) coding on the Java platform for the last decade. I also do all my own stunts.</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor>R.J. Lorimer</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
  <title>Windows 8 & RT Discussions, Thor, Thor .NET and vcap-client Status Updates</title>
  <link>http://realjenius.com/2012/10/30/thor-thor-net-and-vcap-client-status-updates/</link>
  <author>R.J. Lorimer</author>
  <pubDate>2012-10-30T00:00:00-07:00</pubDate>
  <guid>http://realjenius.com/2012/10/30/thor-thor-net-and-vcap-client-status-updates/</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[
     A few updates from the teams:
<h2>Thor</h2>
<p>Thor is moving along with implementation of services starting yesterday (Monday). You can view our live <a href="http://huboard.com/IronFoundry/Thor/board" target="_blank">Huboard Kanban</a> to see what is currently being worked on. The interface in the last few weeks has gotten a faster, cleaner appearance and stabilized even more around deploying and maintaining your Cloud Foundry based environments.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.ironfoundry.org/"><img src="http://adronhall.smugmug.com/Software/Software-Development/Thor/i-fQFJCBP/0/S/square-S.png" alt="" width="180" height="180" /></a></p>
<p>If you're an XCode user and familiar with Git, check out the <a href="https://github.com/IronFoundry/Thor/blob/master/README.md" target="_blank">README.md</a> to pull down the latest code and try it out yourself against your own Cloud Foundry Projects - private or public hosted!</p>

<h2>Thor .NET for Windows Users</h2>
<p>The Windows version of the Thor Client is about to go into beta in the coming weeks. It has an elegant metro style interface and will initially be available for Windows 7.</p>

<p>For the WinRT and Windows 8 versions we're still determining what the best approach is to development of this version of the UI. We'd love any additional input on the WinRT or Windows 8 Applications or how you see you may use the application on WinRT or Windows 8. Let us know in the <a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/?fromgroups=#!topic/ironfoundry/bJJucnSx1Vc" target="_blank">Iron Foundry Discussion Group</a>.</p>
<h2>vcap-client on Nuget</h2>
<p>Recently we released the <a href="https://github.com/IronFoundry/vcap-client" target="_blank">vcap-client library</a> for client usage against any <a href="http://www.cloudfoundry.org" target="_blank">Cloud Foundry</a> and <a href="http://ironfoundry.org" target="_blank">Iron Foundry</a> Built Environments. So if you're a use of the .NET Framework, this library has all the functionality wrapped up in a <a href="http://www.nuget.org/packages/IronFoundry-VcapClient" target="_blank">Nuget Package</a> for you.</p>

<p>So if you're a user of <a href="http://www.appfog.com" target="_blank">AppFog</a>, <a href="http://cloudfoundry.com" target="_blank">CloudFoundry.com</a>, <a href="http://www.tier3.com/services/fabric" target="_blank">Tier 3 Web Fabric</a>, <a href="http://www.activestate.com/stackato" target="_blank">Stackato</a> or another Cloud Foundry enabled environment and write code against the .NET Framework, this is a <a href="http://www.nuget.org/packages/IronFoundry-VcapClient" target="_blank">great library</a> to try out.</p>
<h2>Conversations Around Iron Foundry Library</h2>
<p>We're currently having conversations via the <a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/?fromgroups#!forum/ironfoundry" target="_blank">Iron Foundry Discussion Group</a> for implementing <a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/?fromgroups=#!topic/ironfoundry/qa2c9S88r_o" target="_blank">background services for .NET</a>. Join the conversation if you'd like to contribute, add your suggestions or have any ideas on how this should be implemented.</p>
  ]]></description>
</item>

	<item>
  <title>Latest Alpha Release Features & Additions for the Thor Cloud Foundry UI</title>
  <link>http://realjenius.com/2012/10/15/latest-alpha-release-feature-additions-for-thor/</link>
  <author>R.J. Lorimer</author>
  <pubDate>2012-10-15T00:00:00-07:00</pubDate>
  <guid>http://realjenius.com/2012/10/15/latest-alpha-release-feature-additions-for-thor/</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[
     Hello Thor Users. We're still in alpha with Thor, but I wanted to share some of the latest progress that has been made over the last few weeks. Here's a run down point by point of the latest <a href="https://github.com/IronFoundry/Thor/pull/109" target="_blank">pull request #109</a>:
<ul>
	<li>Button, styles, and related materials are in line with OS-X standards for the workflow screen of deploying an application.</li>
	<li>Deployments for node.js, erlang, java, .NET and the other supported applications now works.</li>
	<li>More unit tests added around new key features, especially detection of the language/framework support.</li>
	<li>Easier to navigate workflow wizard for deployment with appropriate drop out points, etc.</li>
</ul>
As for the next steps, our <a href="https://github.com/IronFoundry/Thor/issues?milestone=8&amp;state=open" target="_blank">list of stories is listed on Github</a>. Get involved and we'll have them knocked out even faster. We'd also love any input on features that are available now or in the future or any code reviews, architecture suggestions, or similar. Just join the <a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/ironfoundry" target="_blank">discussion group</a> and let's talk.

Here's a list of some of the key feature stories coming in our next push:
<ul>
	<li>Thor User wants to be able to add a service to the available services.</li>
	<li>Thor User wants to view a list of services available for use.</li>
	<li>Thor user wants to be able to view multiple bound services for an application.</li>
	<li>Thor User wants to be able to bind a service to an application.</li>
	<li>Thor user wants to see various X parameters for their running services.</li>
	<li>Thor user wants to be able to view available services for their application(s).</li>
</ul>

  ]]></description>
</item>

	<item>
  <title>Contribute to Iron Foundry, Here's How!</title>
  <link>http://realjenius.com/2012/09/12/contribute-to-iron-foundry/</link>
  <author>R.J. Lorimer</author>
  <pubDate>2012-09-12T00:00:00-07:00</pubDate>
  <guid>http://realjenius.com/2012/09/12/contribute-to-iron-foundry/</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[
     We've been asked a few times, "<em>what's the quickest, easiest and fastest way to get the code, build it and contribute back to Iron Foundry?</em>" Here's a quick start for doing just that.

First, there are a few prerequisites that you'll need:
<ul>
	<li>Visual Studio 2010 SP1 w/ all the latest patches, updates, etc.</li>
	<li>Get the latest <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/vstudio/aa496123.aspx" target="_blank">.NET Framework</a> too.</li>
	<li>You'll also need the <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=2680" target="_blank">Visual Studio 2010 SDK</a> if you want to edit or compile the Visual Studio extensions.</li>
	<li>Github Account, <a href="https://github.com/login" target="_blank">sign up here</a>.</li>
</ul>
Once these are met, then navigate over to <a href="http://www.github.com" target="_blank">Github</a> and to the <a href="http://www.github.com/ironfoundry" target="_blank">Iron Foundry Repositories</a>. Here at this time you'll find a number of repositories. Here's a short description of each:
<ul>
	<li><a href="https://github.com/IronFoundry/ironfoundry" target="_blank">IronFoundry</a> - this repo is the core Iron Foundry Project Solution. This is where the Windows DEA, the Cloud Explorer (being replaced by the Thor Project) and other projects to extend Cloud Foundry into the Windows world.</li>
	<li><a href="https://github.com/IronFoundry/cloud_controller" target="_blank">cloud_controller</a> - this repo is a fork that includes all of the updates from the VMware controlled github repos. We have this here to work on while we sync things up, add and extend and test to send pull requests back to the core Cloud Foundry Project.</li>
	<li><a href="https://github.com/IronFoundry/vcap-staging" target="_blank">vcap-staging</a> - another fork of the Cloud Foundry Projects for use among the Iron Foundry Project. Updated regularly from upstream.</li>
	<li><a href="https://github.com/IronFoundry/vcap" target="_blank">vcap</a> - another fork, same as the others. Updated from upstream.</li>
	<li><a href="https://github.com/IronFoundry/vcap-services" target="_blank">vcap-services</a> - fork.</li>
	<li><a href="https://github.com/IronFoundry/vcap-services-base" target="_blank">vcap-services-base</a> - fork.</li>
	<li><a href="https://github.com/IronFoundry/bosh" target="_blank">bosh</a> - fork of the BOSH Project. This project is used for deploying Cloud Foundry &amp; we're working to set it up for use to deploy Iron Foundry bits too.</li>
</ul>
There are a lot of other core repositories and forks, but these are the base ones. The main one you'll want to pull down in order to contribute to is the <a href="https://github.com/IronFoundry/ironfoundry" target="_blank">Iron Foundry Repository</a>.

When you clone the Iron Foundry repo down from Github and open it you'll need to make one setting to make sure everything builds appropriately. We've used Nuget to setup the dependencies and they're pulled down if not available during build time. To make sure that Nuget can do this click on Tools -&gt; Library Package Manager -&gt; Package Manager Settings and in the tree make sure Package Manager has General options displayed. Check the Allow NuGet to download packages during build.

[caption id="attachment_123" align="aligncenter" width="1024"]<a href="http://blog.ironfoundry.org/2012/09/contribute-to-iron-foundry/blurgle/" rel="attachment wp-att-123"><img class="size-large wp-image-123" title="Package Manager Settings" src="/img/blog/blurgle-1024x640.png" alt="Package Manager Settings" width="1024" height="640" /></a> Package Manager Settings[/caption]

Once this is done, select the solution and clean the entire solution. Now click on build or rebuild all, this will now build the entire solution, all the dependencies inline, and pull down any dependencies needed from Nuget.

Over the next few days &amp; weeks we'll take a look at the various Thor Projects &amp; their respective build processes. As always, any comments, questions or otherwise, feel free to let us know in the comments or jump into the <a href="https://groups.google.com/forum/?fromgroups#!forum/ironfoundry" target="_blank">group conversation</a>.

  ]]></description>
</item>

	<item>
  <title>Thor!</title>
  <link>http://realjenius.com/2012/08/27/thor/</link>
  <author>R.J. Lorimer</author>
  <pubDate>2012-08-27T00:00:00-07:00</pubDate>
  <guid>http://realjenius.com/2012/08/27/thor/</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[
     The Iron Foundry project has had an amazing nine months since its launch. Thank you to the entire community for your support and contributions.

With over 3500 downloads and 500 active developers using the free Iron Foundry.ME trial environment, the project has exceeded our expectations.
First, the Iron Foundry team released some powerful tools to support the community including
• Soon after launch we added the NET DEA.
• In February we enabled local development for .NET community with the Micro Iron Foundry
• In April we released the Iron Foundry .ME Environment enabling full Cloud Foundry support + .NET in a free test environment. In addition, we expanded database support to MySQL and Postgres and added support for Rabbit MQ.
• In August we issued an update to the Iron Foundry VMC to keep it in synch with Cloud Foundry.

And, we are very excited not only about the continuing evolution of the available tools, but also the momentum in the industry around Cloud Foundry and Iron Foundry adoption. Among the many highlights:
• Intel -- one of the world’s best IT shops -- recently revealed that they are running Cloud Foundry and Iron Foundry as their internal environment
• The team at Active announced full Stackato integration with Iron Foundry
• New Zealand’s Appsecute launched their Cloud Foundry application management service with support for managing Iron Foundry applications.

Today we are excited to give you a sneak peak at something special the team has been working on we’ll release to the community in September: Project Thor.

Thor -- and its brother Thor.NET -- is the new client tool for managing your Cloud Foundry and Iron Foundry environments from the desktop.  Thor is the OS-X version and Thor.NET is the Windows version. To grab a sneak peak of the UI and to read our thoughts around design, architecture, and our belief in community for these tools go to <a href="http://www.ironfoundry.org/thor">http://www.ironfoundry.org/thor</a>.

[caption id="attachment_118" align="aligncenter" width="300"]<a href="http://blog.ironfoundry.org/2012/08/thor/mac_os_x_1-2/" rel="attachment wp-att-118"><img class="size-medium wp-image-118" title="OS-X Thor" src="/img/blog/mac_os_x_11-300x252.png" alt="OS-X Thor" width="300" height="252" /></a> OS-X Thor[/caption]

[caption id="attachment_119" align="aligncenter" width="300"]<a href="http://blog.ironfoundry.org/2012/08/thor/metro_2/" rel="attachment wp-att-119"><img class="size-medium wp-image-119" title="Windows 8 Sneak Peak" src="/img/blog/metro_2-300x252.png" alt="Windows 8 Sneak Peak" width="300" height="252" /></a> Windows 8 Sneak Peak[/caption]

If you would like to contribute to Thor drop us a note at team@ironfoundry.org.

Thanks!
Jared

  ]]></description>
</item>

	<item>
  <title>Choosing the Right Database Option for Your Iron Foundry Applications</title>
  <link>http://realjenius.com/2012/08/15/choosing-the-right-database-option-for-your-iron-foundry-applications/</link>
  <author>R.J. Lorimer</author>
  <pubDate>2012-08-15T00:00:00-07:00</pubDate>
  <guid>http://realjenius.com/2012/08/15/choosing-the-right-database-option-for-your-iron-foundry-applications/</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[
     Iron Foundry offers a host of database services that developers can leverage when building Iron Foundry applications. While there may not be a “wrong” choice (although in some cases, there are horribly inefficient choices!), how can we choose the best database for the situation at hand? Below, we look at each database option in Iron Foundry and why you would, or would not, select it for your application.

<hr align="left" width="95%" />

<h3>MongoDB</h3>

<hr align="left" width="95%" />

<h4>What is it?</h4>
<a href="http://www.mongodb.org/" target="_blank">MongoDB</a> is a popular open-source NoSQL database. While called a “document database”, MongoDB does not store unstructured documents like PDFs or Microsoft Word files, but rather, stores its data as <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BSON" target="_blank">JSON-like files</a>. Each <strong>document</strong> represents a database record while a <strong>collection</strong> is similar to a database table. However, unlike traditional relational databases with a fixed schema, MongoDB collections have no such restriction and each document could have entirely different fields. Developers use the <a href="http://www.mongodb.org/display/DOCS/SQL+to+Mongo+Mapping+Chart" target="_blank">Mongo Query Language</a> to find records in MongoDB collections. Through the <a href="http://www.mongodb.org/display/DOCS/Drivers" target="_blank">use of drivers</a>, MongoDB supports a wide variety of languages such as Ruby, Scala, C#, Node, Java and more. MongoDB supports a variety of features (such as <a href="http://www.mongodb.org/display/DOCS/Replication" target="_blank">replication</a> and <a href="http://www.mongodb.org/display/DOCS/Indexes" target="_blank">indexing</a>) that you’d typically find in RDMS offerings, but also offers unique capabilities such as <a href="http://www.mongodb.org/display/DOCS/Sharding" target="_blank">auto-sharding</a> and batch processing via <a href="http://www.mongodb.org/display/DOCS/MapReduce" target="_blank">MapReduce</a>.
<h4>When to use it?</h4>
There’s actually an <a href="http://www.mongodb.org/display/DOCS/Use+Cases" target="_blank">excellent page on the MongoDB site</a> that outlines the core use cases and anti-patterns. They also have a <a href="http://www.mongodb.org/display/DOCS/Production+Deployments" target="_blank">useful list of customer stories</a> that explain (sometimes with attachments!) how they are using MongoDB. Basically, MongoDB is a good choice for high performing apps that have complex data objects with a variable schema. Don’t choose MongoDB if you have intense cross-object transactions and heavy SQL coding requirements. While there has been some <a href="http://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=3200683" target="_blank">backlash against MongoDB</a> in the past year, it remains <a href="http://www.theregister.co.uk/2012/06/11/mongo_db/" target="_blank">crazy popular</a> for its performance, approachability and lively ecosystem.

<hr align="left" width="95%" />

<h3>Microsoft SQL Server</h3>

<hr align="left" width="95%" />

<h4>What is it?</h4>
<a href="http://www.microsoft.com/sqlserver/en/us/default.aspx" target="_blank">SQL Server</a> is the flagship database product from Microsoft. It uses a relational structure and is made up of databases, tables and records. The tables in a SQL Server database have a fixed schema made up of typed columns. SQL Server has some of the capabilities that you expect to find in a traditional relational database: stored procedures, indexes, constraints and cross-object transactions. Data is queried through the rich <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/T-SQL" target="_blank">T-SQL</a> syntax that allows variables, a full set of operations for creating/reading/updating/deleting data, control flow statements and more. Starting with SQL Server 2005, developers can also write <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SQL_CLR" target="_blank">stored procedures and triggers based on the .NET language</a>. While SQL Server uses a proprietary data streaming format (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tabular_Data_Stream" target="_blank">TDS</a>), there are still many ways to access SQL Server data from non-Microsoft clients <a href="http://blogs.technet.com/b/dataplatforminsider/archive/2011/08/29/microsoft-aligning-with-odbc.aspx" target="_blank">through ODBC</a>. There are also many libraries to make this easier in <a href="https://github.com/rails-sqlserver/tiny_tds" target="_blank">Ruby</a>, <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=29995" target="_blank">Node</a>, and <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/sqlserver/aa937724.aspx" target="_blank">Java</a>.

While relational databases sometimes get a bad rap for poor scalability, many high volume web sites <a href="http://cacm.acm.org/magazines/2011/6/108663-scalable-sql/fulltext" target="_blank">rely heavily on relational databases like SQL Server</a>. SQL Server consistently <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/sqlserver/en/us/product-info/benchmarks.aspx" target="_blank">ranks as a leader</a> among relational database providers  in “transactions per second” metrics as calculated by TPC.
<h4>When to use it?</h4>
If you have a relatively static data structure and have many objects with inter-relationships, SQL Server is a good choice. Likewise, if you already have an investment in SQL Server tools, then using the Iron Foundry version will be very straightforward. Developers <a href="http://blog.ironfoundry.org/2012/07/web_database_configuration_settings/" target="_blank">can easily use</a> the SQL Server Management Studio against Iron Foundry instances and treat the PaaS database just like one installed locally. Microsoft themselves <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/sqlserver/en/us/product-info/case-studies.aspx" target="_blank">tout use cases</a> for internal business applications, <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/casestudies/Microsoft-SQL-Server-2008-R2-Enterprise/Match.com/Largest-Online-Dating-Service-Gains-Competitive-Edge-with-Microsoft-Solution/710000000118" target="_blank">high volume storage for web applications</a>, and more.

<hr align="left" width="95%" />

<h3>MySQL</h3>

<hr align="left" width="95%" />

<h4>What is it?</h4>
<a href="http://www.mysql.com/" target="_blank">MySQL</a>, now owned by Oracle, claims to be the most popular open source database and is the “M'” in the ubiquitous LAMP (Linux/Apache/MySQL/PHP) web stack. It is a relational database that runs on multiple platforms including Linux, Windows, Mac OS, Solaris and IBM AIX. MySQL has a wide range of capabilities including support for stored procedures, triggers, database views, indexing, and ACID-compliant transactions. Something that’s unique about MySQL (vs other relational databases) is that it offers <a href="http://www.supportsages.com/blog/2010/08/mysql-storage-engines-an-overview-their-limitations-and-an-attempt-for-comparison/" target="_blank">multiple storage engines</a> that can be used for a given table. Some engines support data types that others do not, and some offer differently levels of support for transactions and indexing. There are engines provided natively, as well as engines created by partners and community members. Queries against MySQL data are performed use SQL that should familiar to anyone who has coded against databases in the past. MySQL offers a <a href="http://www.mysql.com/products/connector/" target="_blank">series of drivers</a> for client connectivity and there are plenty of other libraries for technologies like <a href="https://github.com/joyent/node/wiki/modules#wiki-db-mysql" target="_blank">Node</a> and <a href="http://dev.mysql.com/downloads/ruby.html" target="_blank">Ruby</a>.
<h4>When to use it?</h4>
Some of the largest web properties in the world <a href="http://www.mysql.com/customers/" target="_blank">rely on MySQL</a> for their data storage. Many of the same reasons that you would use Microsoft SQL Server apply here as well. Structured data, object relationships, and a need for transactions and indexing. Also, if you already have a skills investment in MySQL, then using MySQL for your Iron Foundry application is a no-brainer. The MySQL team has a very nice article on why you’d <a href="http://dev.mysql.com/tech-resources/articles/move_from_microsoft_SQL_Server.html" target="_blank">choose MySQL over Microsoft SQL Server</a>, and Microsoft has the <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/sqlserver/en/us/product-info/competitor-compare.aspx" target="_blank">same sort of article on their site</a>. You won’t really go wrong with either choice!

<hr align="left" width="95%" />

<h3>Neo4j</h3>

<hr align="left" width="95%" />

<h4>What is it?</h4>
<a href="http://neo4j.org/" target="_blank">Neo4j</a> is an open-source, NoSQL graph database. While many of us are familiar with the other types of NoSQL databases (document databases like MongoDB, or key-value stores like Redis), graph databases are a bit more obscure. Graph databases put a high priority on the relationships between objects and makes it easy to query these relationships. In fact, it’s often <a href="http://adam.heroku.com/past/2010/3/15/graph_databases/" target="_blank">much easier than querying relationships in a relational database</a>! The “things” in a graph database are called a <strong>node</strong>, and the “relationships” are called <strong>edges</strong>. The Neo4j database is Java-based and stores its data on disk. It’s designed to be very fast and also ACID transaction compliant. The database itself can be embedded within an application or deployed as a full-fledged standalone server. While the <a href="http://api.neo4j.org/current/" target="_blank">API</a> places a premium on Java, developers can also access it through an <a href="http://components.neo4j.org/neo4j-server/1.3.M02/rest.html" target="_blank">HTTP/REST interface</a>. Data queries are executed using the <a href="http://docs.neo4j.org/chunked/stable/cypher-query-lang.html" target="_blank">Cypher Query Language</a> which is designed for efficient traversal of graphs.
<h4>When to use it?</h4>
This database will be a great choice for Iron Foundry applications that place a premium on relationships between schema-less data structures. That means that this will be a good fit for social networks, genome analysis, recommendation algorithms <a href="http://www.infoq.com/articles/graph-nosql-neo4j" target="_blank">and more</a>.

<hr align="left" width="95%" />

<h3>PostgreSQL</h3>

<hr align="left" width="95%" />

<h4>What is it?</h4>
<a href="http://www.postgresql.org/" target="_blank">PostgreSQL</a> is an increasingly popular open-source <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Object-relational_database" target="_blank">object-relational</a> database system. You can run PostgreSQL on <a href="http://www.postgresql.org/download/" target="_blank">nearly every operating system</a> including Linux, UNIX, and Windows. It’s a very robust database that is ACID-compliant and has features like joins, views, triggers, stored procedures and <a href="http://www.postgresql.org/docs/9.1/static/external-interfaces.html" target="_blank">native programming interfaces</a> for popular languages/frameworks like Java, .NET, Python, Ruby, ODBC and more. PostgreSQL has a lot of sophisticated features such as <a href="http://www.sai.msu.su/~megera/postgres/gist/doc/intro.shtml" target="_blank">GIST indexing</a>, <a href="http://www.postgresql.org/docs/9.1/static/ddl-inherit.html" target="_blank">table inheritance</a>,  and a <a href="http://www.postgresql.org/docs/9.1/interactive/rules.html" target="_blank">rules system</a>. Queries against the structured tables are done using <a href="http://www.postgresql.org/docs/9.1/interactive/sql.html" target="_blank">SQL</a> and should be easy for any database programmer to use. An <a href="http://wekeroad.com/2012/07/19/postgresql-rising" target="_blank">article about the rise of PostgreSQL</a> generated a <a href="http://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=4268525" target="_blank">lengthy discussion on Hacker News</a> where many proponents and detractors of the platform debated the merits and shortfalls of the platform. It’s a good read.
<h4>When to use it?</h4>
PostgreSQL has some <a href="http://www.postgresql.org/about/users/" target="_blank">prominent customers</a> across industries. You’ll <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/8181604/postgres-9-1-vs-mysql-5-6-innodb" target="_blank">often</a> <a href="http://www.craigkerstiens.com/2012/04/30/why-postgres/" target="_blank">find</a> PostgreSQL compared to MySQL <a href="http://facility9.com/2011/12/ten-reasons-postgresql-is-better-than-sql-server/" target="_blank">or</a> SQL Server. In essence though, consider choosing PostgreSQL for your Iron Foundry application if you want to use an open-source database for a high-performing (web) application that uses SQL queries. It’s a great fit for complex scenarios that can take advantage of the differentiating features like inheritance and advanced query optimization.

<hr align="left" width="95%" />

<h3>Redis</h3>

<hr align="left" width="95%" />

<h4>What is it?</h4>
<a href="http://redis.io/" target="_blank">Redis</a> is a fast, widely used open-source NoSQL database that uses a key-value store paradigm. Data is typically stored in-memory, although now users can optionally snapshot data to disk periodically. It runs on UNIX/Linux/MacOS (although non-production quality ports for Windows exist). Redis supports a handful of <a href="http://redis.io/topics/data-types" target="_blank">data types</a> including strings, lists (of strings), sets (unordered collections of strings), sorted sets and hashes (which are useful for object representations). While optimized for individual key retrieval, database content can be filtered/searched through operations like <a href="http://redis.io/commands/zrange" target="_blank">ZRANGE</a>, <a href="http://redis.io/commands/lrange" target="_blank">LRANGE</a>,  <a href="http://redis.io/commands/getrange" target="_blank">GETRANGE</a> and <a href="http://redis.io/commands" target="_blank">more</a>. Redis also has some cool features like <a href="http://redis.io/commands/expire" target="_blank">content expiration</a>, and a pub/sub engine that opens up a whole host of <a href="http://robots.thoughtbot.com/post/6325247416/redis-pub-sub-how-does-it-work" target="_blank">possibilities</a>. There are a variety of data access libraries available for languages/frameworks like <a href="https://github.com/ServiceStack/ServiceStack.Redis" target="_blank">.NET</a>, <a href="https://github.com/xetorthio/jedis" target="_blank">Java</a>, <a href="https://github.com/mranney/node_redis" target="_blank">Node</a>, <a href="https://github.com/nicolasff/phpredis" target="_blank">PHP</a> and <a href="http://redis.io/clients" target="_blank">many more</a>.
<h4>When to use it?</h4>
Use Redis with your Iron Foundry application when you want blazing speed and have a data set that can sit comfortably in RAM. You would need to be comfortable with the prospects of losing data in the event of a server failure. Many <a href="http://redis.io/topics/whos-using-redis" target="_blank">large organizations are using Redis</a>, often to provide a high performing <a href="http://meta.stackoverflow.com/questions/69164/does-stack-overflow-use-caching-and-if-so-how/69172#69172" target="_blank">caching layer</a> to their application. You’ll also see everything from  storing session data to creating URL shorteners built with Redis.

  ]]></description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>